<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>自用短链接服务</title>
    <link href="/7nm.co/"/>
    <url>/7nm.co/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>7nm.co</strong></p><p>现在 5 个字母以内又好听不贵的域名已经不好找了，找了一晚上才找到这一个 qwq</p><p>见过了许多短域名（b23.tv, 3.cn, t.cn）后，觉得短链接服务确实挺帅的，于是决定自己搭建一个短链接服务。恰好最近在看 VTB，七海 nanami，就买了个 <code>7nm.co</code>，不仅是七海的缩写，还有 7 纳米的含义。</p><p>先写这么多，等短链接的后台服务写好了再来更新这篇博客。我是脆鲨，我永远喜欢 nanami！<img src="/img/7nm.co/c8d01e4cee21632345fbce222c63b21b489eab7a.png@518w.webp" alt="nana7mi"></p>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>WSL2 and Windows Terminal</title>
    <link href="/wsl2/"/>
    <url>/wsl2/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Windows 是最好的 Linux 发行版。</p></blockquote><p>WSL2 发布以后就一直有人这么评论。最近发现 WSL2 和 Windows Terminal 配合起来无比好用。</p><h2 id="效果"><a href="#效果" class="headerlink" title="效果"></a>效果</h2><ul><li>按 Win 键，然后输入 Windows，回车，就能在自己用户文件夹下打开 PowerShell</li><li>按 Win 键，然后输入 Ubuntu，回车，就能在 Linux 用户文件夹下打开 Ubuntu 命令行</li><li>按 Win 键，然后输入 wt，回车，就能在自己用户文件夹下打开 Ubuntu 命令行</li><li>任意文件夹内，右键，选择 在 Windows 终端 中打开，就能在此处打开 PowerShell</li><li>任意文件夹内，右键，选择 在 Windows 终端 预览版 中打开，就能在此处打开 Ubuntu 命令行</li></ul><h2 id="操作"><a href="#操作" class="headerlink" title="操作"></a>操作</h2><ol><li>准备两个 Windows Terminal（Windows Terminal 和 Windows Terminal Preview）</li><li>设置默认终端应用程序为 Windows Terminal Preview（在 Windows Terminal 的设置里面可以找到这个选项）</li><li>在 Windows Terminal Preview 的设置里面，将默认配置文件改成 WSL2（比如 Ubuntu）</li></ol>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Google Summer of Code 2021 Final Evaluation</title>
    <link href="/gsoc-report/"/>
    <url>/gsoc-report/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is my final evaluation of Google Summer of Code 2021.</p><p>I worked in Casbin this summer, and my job is to write code for <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor">Casdoor</a> and <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode">Casnode</a>. Click the link to read <a href="https://archives.kininaru.dev/gsoc/2021/proposal.pdf">My Proposal of Google Summer of Code 2021</a>.</p><p>The first part of this report is a brief summary of my work. For detailed contributions, please read the summary of pull requests below.</p><h1 id="Summary"><a href="#Summary" class="headerlink" title="Summary"></a>Summary</h1><p>Here are some big features I implemented for Casdoor and Casnode. In addition, I also fixed bugs for both of them.</p><h2 id="Casdoor"><a href="#Casdoor" class="headerlink" title="Casdoor"></a>Casdoor</h2><p>Casdoor is a Single-Sign-On platform based on OAuth 2.0 / OIDC. It can also serve as a service provider (you can use Casdoor to send Emails, upload files, set an avatar). My work during Google Summer of Code is to implement some of these functions, and add new features to it.</p><p><strong>Support avatar tailoring uploading:</strong> This is the first contribution I made to Casbin community. I spent almost a week learning the file structure of Casdoor, Golang and React, then I talked to my mentor about the details and the front end UI. It was really excited to see the PR was merged in the end. After this, I became familiar with the process of making a contribution to the community, so things became easy after that.</p><p><strong>go-sms-sender and the verification code:</strong> There are many SMS providers in mainland China. Each of them has a different API and SDK. So it is not easy to adapt all of them. To keep the code of Casdoor clean and easy to understand, I developed <a href="https://github.com/casdoor/go-sms-sender">go-sms-sender</a>. It is designed to use all kinds of SMS providers easily. Only few lines of code is needed to send a SMS via the sender. With go-sms-sender, I also implemented the function of sending verification code via Email and SMS for Casdoor.</p><p><strong>Turing test:</strong> Users are required to pass a Turing test before sending a verification code to their Emails or Phones.</p><p><strong>Casdoor SDKs:</strong> Casdoor is written in Golang, but it supports many languages. Casdoor uses HTTP requests to communicate with those SDKs. I participated in the development of Casdoor Go SDK, Casdoor JS SDK (supported popup sign in and sign up), Casdoor Java SDK, and reviewed the code of Casdoor PHP SDK.</p><h2 id="Casnode"><a href="#Casnode" class="headerlink" title="Casnode"></a>Casnode</h2><p>Casnode is the official forum of Casbin. Casnode is suitable for open source organizations to use because it supports the two-way synchronization to Google Groups, and can sync its topics and replies to all mailing lists.</p><p><strong>Night mode:</strong> I supported the night mode for Casnode. Now, users can click the switch button to switch between night mode and light mode.</p><p><strong>Refactored the OSS support:</strong> Casnode uses Aliyun STS as a storage provider before. This not that safe because users can upload any file to anywhere in the storage server. I refactored the storage system with another Go module called qor, which supports variables of storage providers, and upload these files in the backend, which is safer than before.</p><p><strong>Server side rendering:</strong> Casnode is written in React, which means that bots from search engines can not get the forum details because they can not execute JS code. I used Chromedp in Golang backend, and added a filter for bots. If a HTTP request has a <code>bot</code> keyword in its <code>User-Agent</code>, it will be recognized by the bot filter, and will receive a rendered page with forum details. This way, you can get the information of the forum from search engines.</p><p><strong>Mailing list support:</strong> Casnode sends Emails to a mailing list when new topics or new replies are made. It can sync all new topics and replies to all mailing lists, and supports the two-way synchronization to Google Groups. This made Casnode suitable for open source organizations to use.</p><p><strong>Embeded plugin:</strong> I implemented the embeded plugin for Casnode. With the plugin, only few lines of HTML code is needed to embed Casnode as a reply plugin to any webpage. For example, <a href="https://oa.casbin.com/">Casbin OA</a> uses Casnode  Embedded Plugin as a reply plugin.</p><h1 id="Contributions"><a href="#Contributions" class="headerlink" title="Contributions"></a>Contributions</h1><p>Here are my contributions to Casbin community.</p><h2 id="Open-Issues"><a href="#Open-Issues" class="headerlink" title="Open Issues"></a>Open Issues</h2><ul><li>Open Issue <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/issues/178">Balance didn’t refresh after receiving “today’s checkin bonus”</a></li><li>Open Issue <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/issues/20">A suggestion for README.md</a></li><li>Open Issue <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/issues/159">Forum website login error</a></li><li>Open Issue <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casbin.js/issues/34">The installation commands in the docs do not work properly</a></li><li>Open Issue <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/issues/170">Add a self check at the beginning of the program</a></li><li>Open Issue <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/issues/323">Add a self check when the program starts</a></li></ul><h2 id="Open-Pull-Requests"><a href="#Open-Pull-Requests" class="headerlink" title="Open Pull Requests"></a>Open Pull Requests</h2><ul><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/185">fix: notification bug</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/183">fix: bonus bug and Chinese translation missing</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/34">feat: add go backend API docs</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/33">feat: Go backend API docs</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/32">Fix: Avatar uploading failed</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/180">fix: converted sts to qor</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/179">feat: convert Aliyun STS to qor/oss</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/177">fix: member page links bug</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/175">fix: rich text editor img bug</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/173">fix: rich list bug</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/169">feat: add sensitive words block</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/166">fix: node bugs</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/static/pull/5">feat: added imgs and css for forum night mode</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/164">feat: added night mode</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/static/pull/4">add: night.js for casbin-forum</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/23">feat: added avatar tailoring and uploading</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/22">Support avatar tailoring and updating</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/21">added explainations to Dev and Prod usage in README</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casbin-website/pull/178">added details about EnforceEx()</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casbin-website/pull/176">Fix: https://github.com/casbin/casbin-website/issues/82</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casbin-website/pull/175">Fix: Error document</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casbin-website/pull/173">added Casbin RBAC and RBAC96</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casbin-website/pull/172">added Casbin RBAC and RBAC96</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casbin-website/pull/170">added a tutorial for APIs</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/51">feat: add info about MySQL and Postgres in readme</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/50">feat: add pg for db adapter</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/google-groups-crawler/pull/3">feat: recognize google group email correctly</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/224">feat: sync google group conversations to Casnode</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/google-groups-crawler/pull/2">fix: typo in readme</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/google-groups-crawler/pull/1">feat: init commit</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/223">feat: added Mailing List</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/222">feat: node header image</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/221">fix: node background image uploading failed</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/static/pull/8">fix: add min width to desktop pages</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/217">feat: added cdp for ssr</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/216">fix: avatar display error in topic page</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/static/pull/7">fix: picture too wide in notification page</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/215">fix: reply box height and avatar too small</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/214">add reset username and fixed HTML tag display error</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/212">fix: img doesn’t show in richtext editor replies</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/211">fix: page didn’t jump on mobile UI and reply links</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/210">fix: reload replies from backend incorrectly</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/207">refactor: rewrite topic page logic</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/206">fix: reply page bug and admin new node page crash</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casnode/casnode-website/pull/1">Initialized docusaurus files and added CI</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/205">made last page the default page of reply box, and made auto jump smooth</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/203">feat: auto jump when reply is not in the first page</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/201">fix: login check bug</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/static/pull/6">fix: mobile select2 and casnode reply img error</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/193">fix: made casnode adapt the layout according to the page size</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/190">feat: convert casbin forum to casnode</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/187">fix: rich text editor doesn’t refresh after replying</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/186">fix: text colors are not in effect</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casdoor/casdoor-website/pull/9">feat: add provider intro</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casdoor/casdoor-website/pull/7">feat: add basic intro to Casdoor</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/73">fix: removed outdated lines in README</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/250">feat: use retro style when user did not set gravatar</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/249">fix: add Re to mailing list replies</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/244">fix: print log when the cookie expires</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/243">feat: update crawler to the latest version</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/google-groups-crawler/pull/16">fix: http client aren’t closed</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/google-groups-crawler/pull/15">refactor: rewrite all logic</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/google-groups-crawler/pull/14">fix: Conversation message split</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/google-groups-crawler/pull/13">fix: Conversation message error</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/google-groups-crawler/pull/12">refactor: rewrite crawler logic to get conversations</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/google-groups-crawler/pull/11">fix: code won’t exit when an Internet error happened</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/google-groups-crawler/pull/10">feat: add cookies when getting messages</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/237">fix: invalid date for Google group messages</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/google-groups-crawler/pull/9">fix: time syntax error in Google groups conversations</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/google-groups-crawler/pull/8">feat: get conversation start time</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/70">feat: turing test before sending code</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/66">feat: intergrate verification code countdown as a component</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/63">feat: check email and phone number when signing up</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/229">feat: upload avatar to oss when sync from google group</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casdoor/casdoor-java-sdk/pull/1">feat: Maven project init and add getUsers() getOrganizations() API</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/google-groups-crawler/pull/7">fix: add judgement to avoid crashing</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/57">fix: remove all dom APIs from the project</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/56">Fixed reset phone email data error and removed dom API from ResetModal.js</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/55">feat: add reset Email and phone by using verification code.</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casdoor/go-sms-sender/pull/1">Add Tencent Cloud and Aliyun as providers</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/54">feat: set password for users</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/226">feat: update crawler to v0.0.6 to remove quote from replies</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/google-groups-crawler/pull/6">feat: removed gmail quote from replies</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/225">feat: auto create user during synchronization from Google Groups</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/google-groups-crawler/pull/5">fix: added some judgement to avoid crashing</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/google-groups-crawler/pull/4">feat: add author name to email mapping</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casnode/casnode-website/pull/11">feat: add architecture overview, main-package, routers, controllers</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/295">Add low version SQL support to search</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/287">Removed keywords in html Tags when searching</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/279">Add nil judgements to balance and notification backend to avoid crashing and fixed avatar error in search results</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casnode/casnode-website/pull/7">feat: add get started page</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/273">feat: in-site search for topics</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/268">fix: update crawler to v0.1.2 to avoid crashing</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/267">fix: signup bug</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/google-groups-crawler/pull/17">fix: http response nil</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/263">feat: convert to casdoor go sdk</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casdoor/casdoor-go-sdk/pull/2">fix: remove panic in internet errors to avoid crashing</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/85">fix: redirect urls null in app-built-in</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casdoor/casdoor-go-sdk/pull/1">feat: add update delete User</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/84">fix: wrong usement in getUsername</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/76">feat: authorize via clientId and clientSecret</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casnode/casnode-embed-js/pull/2">Basic Code</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casdoor/casdoor-website/pull/37">fix: nginx reload command</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/202">feat: expose email and sms APIs as services to SDK</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/198">feat: integrate Storage config into providers</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/196">feat: integrate OSS into providers</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/329">feat: use Casdoor SDK to signup</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/185">Customized OAuth provider login URL</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/321">Added Casdoor JS SDK</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/319">feat: add react lazyload</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/153">feat: auto login session will expire after 24h</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/149">feat: support SAML okta login</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/node-casbin/redis-adapter/pull/6">feat: add auto release CI</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/static/pull/18">added a new Button component.</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/316">feat: add Button component</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casdoor/casdoor-js-sdk/pull/7">feat: add semantic release</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/363">fix: code mirror editor display bugs</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/358">feat: Hide Nodes and Topics</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casdoor/casdoor-js-sdk/pull/6">feat: support popup window</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casbin-oa/pull/14">feat: use casdoor-js-sdk to signin and signup</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/357">fix: add nodeId in getTopicByUrlAndTitle</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casbin-oa/pull/13">feat: add Casnode embed plguin</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casdoor/go-sms-sender/pull/3">feat: change provider name</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/354">feat: login in embed reply</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/252">feat: add VolcEngine as a SMS provider</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/249">feat: update go-sms-sender to v0.0.2 to support VolcEngine</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/351">feat: add router and APIs for embed plugin</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/350">Embed plugin</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/347">Add API to get topic by url and title</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casdoor/casdoor-go-sdk/pull/9">feat: modified user, and return user directly</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/220">feat: add user initScore in app.conf</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/342">feat: add user initScore in app.conf</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/218">refactor: use ResponseError to response error</a></li><li>Open PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/213">fix: use ReponseError to response error</a></li></ul><h2 id="Review-Pull-Requests"><a href="#Review-Pull-Requests" class="headerlink" title="Review Pull Requests"></a>Review Pull Requests</h2><ul><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/247#pullrequestreview-671704807">fix: all codemirror focus area</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/246#pullrequestreview-671422215">fix: Perfect the function of add node</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/72#pullrequestreview-670363168">feat: add “forget password” [front &amp; backend]</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/242#pullrequestreview-669771999">feat: Add new member in UI #194</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/241#pullrequestreview-669764803">fix: codemirror textarea focus area</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/238#pullrequestreview-668703725">feat:Add advertisement banners to the forum</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/132#pullrequestreview-693382559">feat: add password Item forcibly</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/313#pullrequestreview-692457034">add check node info on add new topic and reply</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/117#pullrequestreview-689435765">fix: improve i18n and add some translation</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/305#pullrequestreview-689177408">fix: Return to the previous page after language selection</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/303#pullrequestreview-687907113">fix: sync google group attachment files to links</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/google-groups-crawler/pull/18#pullrequestreview-687886977">fix: sync attachment files</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/298#pullrequestreview-687827018">feat: add member and poster swagger api docs</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/111#pullrequestreview-686355298">fix: Merge the same translation words #108</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/285#pullrequestreview-686349241">feat: add topic and account swagger api docs</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/284#pullrequestreview-686070533">feat: migrate beego from v1.x to v2.x</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/283#pullrequestreview-685314829">fix: user balance not updated after login #276</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/107#pullrequestreview-684038545">feat: Allow the user to sign up with OAuth</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/277#pullrequestreview-682790770">fix: The administrator cannot enter the administrator background #275</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/274#pullrequestreview-682413949">fix: Fix the debug warnings in browser console #269</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/102#pullrequestreview-682411165">feat: Allow the user to sign up with OAuth</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/272#pullrequestreview-682331150">fix: Fix the bug that the ad doesn’t show up for anonymous access #270</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/92#pullrequestreview-678096847">feat: allow user signup with oauth</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/259#pullrequestreview-676278571">feat: Add auto-generated topic tags</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/253#pullrequestreview-674420635">feat: users can add tags to posts when they publish them #197</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/75#pullrequestreview-673767651">feat: add “forget password” [front &amp; backend]</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/340#pullrequestreview-718769483">refactor: change jsdelivr to cdn.casbin.org</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/336#pullrequestreview-716738317">fix: topic author error and memberbox fresh</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casdoor/casbin-oa-android/pull/9#pullrequestreview-716734713">feat: implement the basic framework of casbin-oa app</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/335#pullrequestreview-715497704">refactor: change cdn</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casdoor/casdoor-js-sdk/pull/2#pullrequestreview-714789168">feat: general implement</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/189#pullrequestreview-713620711">feat: improve ApplicationEditPage</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/187#pullrequestreview-713054019">feat: fix header bugs, improve UI, optimize touchscreen experience</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casbin-oa/pull/6#pullrequestreview-703997675">feat: You can get Prs from github automatically</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/160#pullrequestreview-703919548">feat: support LDAP</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/150#pullrequestreview-702138627">feat: Add log table and record all user behaviors into the table, add UI to view logs</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/148#pullrequestreview-700657858">feat: support 2fa</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/146#pullrequestreview-700574269">feat: support login UI customization</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casnode/casnode-website/pull/17#pullrequestreview-699333174">feat: add installation by BT panel</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casdoor/casdoor-php-sdk/pull/2#pullrequestreview-699328336">Add the code.</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/317#pullrequestreview-698680205">feat: Install Casnode by BT panel</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casbin-oa/pull/4#pullrequestreview-698567609">fix: Correct a small bug</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/143#pullrequestreview-698564255">feat: Integrate Crowdin</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casnode/pull/348#pullrequestreview-728195139">feat: add frontconf management</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casdoor/go-sms-sender/pull/2#pullrequestreview-727139514">Add VolcEngine SMS service support</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/239#pullrequestreview-725974995">fix:  table errors in frontend</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/224#pullrequestreview-724808035">feat: support local storage</a></li><li>Review PR <a href="https://github.com/casbin/casdoor/pull/217#pullrequestreview-720401001">feat: mount app.conf to container</a></li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>我与 Apple</title>
    <link href="/apple/"/>
    <url>/apple/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>8 月 7 日早上，我听说 iCloud 相册会对用户上传的图片进行审查。随后我找到了<a href="https://www.apple.com/child-safety/">原文</a>，证实了这一消息。</p><p>这个新政策的大意是，对于某一类特定的违规图片，iCloud 会在上传前分析内容。如果违规，就提取特征上报。如果这个特征的上报次数到了一个阈值，并且在一个给定的库中，又通过了人工审核，Apple 就会禁用你的账户，并且举报你。</p><p>很早开始，我就模糊地意识到，互联网上没有隐私。对于我存放在所谓“私人云盘”里面的内容，我觉得只要不被删除或者篡改，哪怕直接公开在网上，我都不是非常介意。也就是说，我对于云盘的底线是，资料能完整地保存下来。毕竟上传到云盘，很大一个目的就是备份。</p><p>但是 Apple 这个新政策却告诉我：<strong>我的每一张照片，从规则上，都是可以被直接删掉的。</strong></p><p>刚开始的几个小时内，我非常矛盾。因为 Apple 这个行为是防止犯罪的，而我也支持防止犯罪，但这又触及了我的底线。在网上看了一些文章后，我逐渐理清了思路。在一封对 Apple 的公开信中，我读到了这些内容：</p><blockquote><p><em>“It’s impossible to build a client-side scanning system that can only be used for sexually explicit images sent or received by children. As a consequence, even a well-intentioned effort to build such a system will break key promises of the messenger’s encryption itself and open the door to broader abuses […] That’s not a slippery slope; that’s a fully built system just waiting for external pressure to make the slightest change.”</em></p></blockquote><p>Apple 的这个新系统，不可能只针对这类违规行为。只要外部施压，这些代码就可以找出任何类型的图片。现在，这些代码只在美国生效，并且只针对这类行为，但是以后呢？结合这个观点，我再次确认：<strong>我的任何资料，都是潜在的删除对象。</strong></p><p>于是，我关掉了我的 iCloud 云盘，并且停用 Apple Music，以后我可能也不会再买 Apple 的任何服务了。</p><h2 id="初识"><a href="#初识" class="headerlink" title="初识"></a>初识</h2><p>第一次听说 Apple 是小学的时候。</p><p>小学的时候大家都在用按键机，最高级的功能也就是跑一点 Java 游戏，浏览器一类的应用更是从来没想过。</p><p>然后我认识了 iPhone 4。当时满大街都是它的广告。对于刚刚有一部按键机的我来说，iPhone 简直就是一个无法理解的东西。我没法想象一个手机只有4个按键，任何操作靠点屏幕就能做到。</p><p>iPhone 4 对于我来说太过震撼，以至于数年后我上了初中，见到有同学还在用 iPhone 4，借来看了一下，发现有点卡，惊讶地问他：iPhone 还会卡吗？我熟练使用的按键机从来不会卡住，我下意识认为 iPhone 也是不可能卡的。</p><p>从那时开始，我就一直关注 Apple 的新产品。在新闻联播上看到 iPhone 5 发售，还挺激动的。</p><h2 id="插曲"><a href="#插曲" class="headerlink" title="插曲"></a>插曲</h2><blockquote><p>我最初接触的电子产品就是 Android 手机。直到现在，我还在折腾 Android，用的是 Pixel Experience 系统。使用 Android 的经历对我来说不能算是插曲，而应该是主线。但这是一篇关于 Apple 的文章，所以我还是把这段叫做“插曲”吧。</p></blockquote><p>随着时代的发展，我也用上了智能机，一部杂牌机。至今我都记得，版本号是 Android 4.0.3。</p><p>那部手机配置非常差，只有 128M 内存。当时主流智能机都是 1G 内存，我爹用的小米 2s 是 2G，我娘用的 HTC 是 1G。</p><p>我其实挺感谢那部手机的。正因为它配置差，我学会了折腾。我整天翻它的设置项，看看能不能再挤出一点内存来运行 Minecraft，或者同时打开 QQ 和浏览器。再过了一些时间，我学会了 Root，删掉了一些预装的垃圾。通过一个过量申请内存然后释放的软件挤出尽可能多的内存。我至今还记得第一次看到剩余内存大于 64M 时激动的心情。杂牌机当然不会有第三方 Rom，所以我学会刷机是稍微晚一点的事了。</p><p>正因为我有这段折腾经历，我比一般的人更了解一些底层的事情。在这个靠水军和 PPT 的时代，我能保留一些原始人的理智。如果我当时用的是 iPhone，可能永远都学不会这些。</p><h2 id="狂热"><a href="#狂热" class="headerlink" title="狂热"></a>狂热</h2><p>然后我用上了 iPhone。虽然之前零零散散也用过几次 iOS，但是第一次正经用 iPhone 还是高中。当时为了联络补课的老师，我得到了一部家长退役下来的 iPhone 6 plus。2019 年去用一部 2014 年发布的手机，它理所应当地非常慢。虽然慢，但我还是惊讶于 iOS 精致的 UI。</p><p>与 Android 不同，iOS 的控件非常灵动。非线性动画，各种花里胡哨的变换，还有出人意料的交互逻辑，让我不止一次去思考，这种效果应该如何优雅地去实现。</p><p>iOS 一次又一次地刷新我的认知，原来 UI 还可以做成这样。早年折腾 Android 的经验告诉我，这些东西不过是应用层面的炫技，如果一切照搬，那么 Android 大概率也能做出这种效果。但最终狂热战胜了理智，我开始不顾一切地支持 Apple。虽然从现在清醒的视角来看，Apple 十分封闭，并且它依赖这个封闭无理地抬高价格，依靠一手应用层面的联动来打造生态。这是可以超越的，并不是神。</p><p>上了大学之后我有了自己的电脑。数周后，我开始尝试黑苹果。花了 3 天整，我终于搞定了所有麻烦，成功进入了系统。macOS 给我带来的冲击并没有 iOS 那么猛烈。从 UI 上来看，macOS 和我之前用过的任何 Linux 发行版对比，都没有很大的区别，无非就是更精致了。</p><p>但是对于一个失去理智的粉丝来说，只要能看到 Apple 的 LOGO 就足够了。2020 年，Apple 发布了 M1 芯片。数月之后我入手了一台 Mac mini，这是我第一次用白苹果。即使是冷静后的现在来看，M1 芯片还是很优秀的，无论是打开程序，还是编译代码，速度都是翻倍地快。</p><h2 id="破灭"><a href="#破灭" class="headerlink" title="破灭"></a>破灭</h2><p>Apple 的 UI 实在是过于美好，美好到抑制了我的一些想法。</p><blockquote><p>谷歌有猫病。大家都下意识把谷歌看作一只猫猫。</p><p>猫猫犯错的时候，我们都会说：哎呀，猫猫打翻了水杯，但没关系，毕竟它只是一只猫猫啊！</p></blockquote><p>某种意义上，我也把 Apple 看作了一只猫。只要 Apple 不触碰我的底线，那我就能一直追捧它。</p><p>我的一位朋友也经常试图把我从这个困境中拉出来：</p><blockquote><p>Apple 的联动都是应用层面的，UI 更是表层的东西。任何厂商只要投入足够的资源，都能造出这些东西来。</p></blockquote><p>而我当时并不接受：</p><blockquote><p>应用层做得好也是好。</p></blockquote><p>而现在，这个形象已经彻底崩塌了。如同一开始说的，Apple 开始限制我在 iCloud 上面自由存放东西的权力了。iCloud 本身出问题并不能牵连到整个 Apple，事实上我一开始也只是打算停用 iCloud 相册。但这件事是一个引子，我仔细回忆了这些年我心底那个“理智”所控诉的一切，然后发现 Apple 并没有我想象的那么美好，于是一切崩塌。</p><h2 id="将来"><a href="#将来" class="headerlink" title="将来"></a>将来</h2><p>iCloud 审查内容的代码在 macOS 12 才会上线，我的 Mac 现在还是 macOS 11，但即使 Apple 撤回这个决定，我也不会更新到 12。一想到这家公司的所作所为，我内心就有一种抗拒感。祝愿高通研制出对标 Apple Silicon 的芯片，也祝愿 Linux 越做越好，让更多人拥抱开源。</p><p><strong>2021-09-23 update</strong> </p><p>现在已经卖掉了 mac，入手了一台轻薄本，Windows 11 还是挺不错的。以后不会用任何 Apple 的产品了，并且反对一切与 Apple 有关的东西（Apple 的艺术设计除外，他们的艺术设计还是可以肯定的）。</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Google Summer of Code</title>
    <link href="/gsoc/"/>
    <url>/gsoc/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>今年申请了 Google Summer of Code，向 Casbin 社区投递了 <a href="https://archives.kininaru.dev/gsoc/2021/proposal.pdf">Proposal</a>。</p><p>5 月 18 日收到了 Google 的邮件：</p><p><img src="https://archives.kininaru.dev/gsoc/2021/gsoc-accepted.png" alt="Accepted Email"></p>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>About</title>
    <link href="/about/"/>
    <url>/about/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="关于我"><a href="#关于我" class="headerlink" title="关于我"></a>关于我</h2><ul><li>大三</li><li>C++ 爱好者，认为手动 GC 才是工程师的浪漫</li><li>Golang, Javascript, TypeScript（生活所迫）</li><li>正在学习算法（实际上是魔法）</li><li>（前）Apple 爱好者，现在抵制 Apple 的一切事物（除了 Apple 的设计风格）</li></ul><h2 id="联系我"><a href="#联系我" class="headerlink" title="联系我"></a>联系我</h2><p>Email: <a href="mailto:&#109;&#x65;&#64;&#x6d;&#x61;&#x69;&#108;&#x2e;&#x6b;&#105;&#110;&#105;&#110;&#x61;&#x72;&#117;&#46;&#x64;&#101;&#118;">&#109;&#x65;&#64;&#x6d;&#x61;&#x69;&#108;&#x2e;&#x6b;&#105;&#110;&#105;&#110;&#x61;&#x72;&#117;&#46;&#x64;&#101;&#118;</a></p><p>GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/Kininaru">Kininaru</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>
